Loaders为我们提供了一个可异步加载数据的框架
Loaders provide a framework to perform asynchronous loading of data.
它们通过一个唯一ID注册到一个LoaderManager上
They are registered by ID with a loader manager, which allows them to live
它可让其所管理的Loader的生命周期长于Loader所关联的activity或fragment
beyond the life cycle of the activity or fragment they are associated with.
除了可以异步加载数据之外  Loader还会监视数据源的一举一动
In addition to loading data, loaders include mechanisms to monitor the source
并在内容改变时发送新的结果
of their data, and deliver new results when the contents change.
到目前为止我们已经用过AsyncTask从网络和Sunshine中
Up till now, we've used AsyncTask to load data from the internet and
获取数据
Sunshine.
通常的做法是在onCreate方法中创建AsyncTask的实例
We typically create our AsyncTask in the onCreate method of our activity.
它会新开启一个后台线程
It starts a thread which begins a background task.
如果旋转设备屏幕
If we rotate the device, or
或者其他事件触发activity重启时
do something else that requires the activity to be restarted,
就会有另外一个新的AsyncTask在后台执行操作
we'll create another AsyncTask to do the background operation.
如果要同时
We'll create extra network usage, or
从网络和文件中读取数据
file system usage as both threads run in parallel.
这会花挺长的一段时间才能让用户看到加载完成后的效果
And, it'll take a longer time for the user to see the result of the load.
AsyncTaskLoader实现了和AsyncTask同样的功能
The AsyncTask Loader implements the same functionality as Async Task, but
不过由于AsyncTaskLoader继承自loader  其生命周期与AsyncTask有所不同
because it's a loader, it's lifecycle is different.
改用AsyncTaskLoader  当旋转设备时
With an Async Task Loader, once we rotate the device,
LoaderManager会确保让原有的Loader在
the loader manager will make sure that the old loader is connected to
AsyncTaskLoader重新加载之后还与其保持联系
the Async Task Loader equivalent of on post execute.
看一下onLoadFinished方法
The onLoadFinished function.
Loader所在线程会在loadInBackground中持续运行
The loader thread keeps running in the loadInBackground function, and
而一旦它完成了这个activity就会通过onLoadFinished方法得到通知
once it finishes the activity gets notified through onLoadFinished.
CursorLoader类是从AsyncTaskLoader类是衍生出来的
CursorLoader is derived from Async Task Loader but
而且还有一些额外的优化
has an additional optimization.
在activity重新创建之前  如果游标已经加载过数据
If the cursor has already finished loading and
并且还存在于后台线程之中
load in background before the activity restarts,
CursorLoader就会在初始化时识别出该游标的数据
the CursorLoader recognizes this during the loader initialization.
通过onLoadFinished方法  游标的内容会立刻被显示出来
And the cursor is immediately delivered to the UI through onLoadFinished